Preliminary Guide to the Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW) Archives, 1985-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW) Archives 1985-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW)
7.5 linear feet Extent: 600 Items
Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW) was a Raleigh-based advertising agency that operated from 1985-2009. Accession (2009-0133) includes CDs, videotapes, DVDs, samples of print advertisements, awards, and USB drives with documents from RBW. Clients include Glaxo, Cort, Dollar Tree, Volvo, and Reed's.
RL.10148
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted for 5 years on unpublished materials.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW) Archives were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Historical Note
Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW) was an integrated marketing communications agency that was based in Raleigh, North Carolina, and had clients including BB&T, CORT, Glaxo, Volvo, Dollar Tree, and Reed's. It opened in 1985 and by 1997 had over 120 employees, but declined in size and operations over the next decade. RBW suffered serious financial losses due to clients' trimmed advertising budgets, finally closing permanently in February 2009.
Collection Overview
The collection was acquired as Rockett, Burkhead & Winslow (RBW) was closing in Spring of 2009. It consists of posterboards with sample advertisements; videotapes and DVDs of commercials; CDs with advertisements and other client-related materials; USB flash drives with RBW documents (these have been copied to Duke's Electronic Records server); and awards and trophies from various organizations for excellence in advertising.
Collection Arrangement
This collection is unprocessed; it has been reboxed in the condition that it arrived. CDs were labelled according to date or client, but they have not been sorted or arranged further. There has been no attempt to verify the accuracy of labels.
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2009-0133), 1985-2009, (8 boxes)
  - Unlabelled binder (Box 1)
  - CenturyTel (Box 1)
  - Distributor and Designer Program Guide, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Misys (Box 1)
  - SpectraSite (Box 1)
  - Reed (Box 1)
  - Eaton (Box 1)
  - 2006 Triangle Addys (awards)
    - Silver: CenturyTel TV Campaign (Box 1)
    - Gold: Advertising Industry Self-Promotion: 2006 Triangle Addy Campaign (Box 1)
  - Videotapes
    - RBL&W Medley: Glaxo Wellcome, CORT, Duke Medical Center; May 14 1998 (Box 1)
    - RBWU: Dynamic Branding, Session One; July 7, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Dollar Tree: Believe It! (Box 1)
    - RBW: Demo Reel (Box 1)
    - RBW: Agency Reel, Job 1278, Glaxo; Aug. 22, 2002 (Box 1)
    - RBW: Agency Reel, version 2, Job 1258; July 17, 2002 (Box 1)
    - North Carolina Community College System: It's Working; Apr. 12, 2002 (Box 1)
  - The Best in Medical Advertising and Graphics (Box 1)
  - The Best in Exhibition Stand Design: 2 (Box 1)
  - ADLA 4 (Box 1)
  - Annual of Ad Productions in Japan, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - The Show, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Mobius awards (Box 2)
    - Even the Peas, Shooting at Yankees, Forget Bull Run Campaign, 1993. Recreation: Sporting Events (Box 2)
    - You Searched the Country for the Perfect Shot, 1993. Services: Professional Services (Box 2)
    - Womb, Paint in the Garage, Won't Stand Campaign, 1992. Public Service Announcements (Box 2)
    - All he needs is a little TLC and a gram and a half a week, 1992. Public Service Announcements [plaque is dislodged from marble] (Box 3)
    - In a place where even the peas have black eyes, 1993. Recreation: Sporting Events [plaque is dislodged from marble] (Box 3)
  - Telly Award: Marvel-Superheroes, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Volvo samples (Box 3)
  - Sample advertisements (Box 4)
    - Volvo (Box 4)
    - GlaxoWellcome (Box 4)
    - BB&T (Box 4)
  - CDs, with dates (Box 5)
  - CDs and DVDs, with clients (Box 6-8)
  - Oversize advertisements (Opaperfolder 1)